What is data structure?
Data structure is a storage that is used to store and organize data.
It is a way for arranging data on a computer so that it can be accessed and updated efficiently, depending
on your requirement and the project.
It is important to choose the right data structure for your project.
Example, for data on data structure it that array.
So consider you have an array of numbers and they are stored in an array of integers.
In order to facilitate this storage and the accessing of these elements, and they are numbered from
zero to five in this index.
Index type data structure now data structure in real life where we see data structure.
For example, we have a leaderboard for games and apps, so we use the arrays.
Image processing.
We used metrics or 2D arrays in order to make image processing and using the metrics and metrics uses
with 2D arrays.
The music player like switching between and swiping between that next songs, we have used the length
and less.
The history of visited sites on Chrome or other browser, we use this tack.
And line of people waiting to get through a checkpoint, it is using the queue.
So all of these data structure we are, we are going to learn about them in details and through the
course.
So these data structure in real life are very important to understand that.